jcpportraits.com 2019-06-14

# Privacy Policy | JCPenney Portraits

**Privacy Policy**

Welcome to jcpportraits.com (the “ **Site** ”), operated by Lifetouch Portrait Studios Inc. dba JCPenney Portraits, in partnership with J.C. Penney Company Inc. Together with its [corporate affiliates ](https://www.jcpportraits.com/companyandbrands)(collectively, " **Lifetouch** ," " **we** ," " **our** ," **or** " **us** "), Lifetouch is a trusted provider of photographic products and services to families, communities, schools, churches, day care centers and other organizations throughout the United States and Canada. At Lifetouch, we are sensitive to the privacy concerns of the individuals we photograph and of visitors to our websites, and we want you to know that your privacy is important to us.

 **What does this Policy cover?**  
Unless we notify you otherwise in connection with a particular activity, this Privacy Policy  explains how we collect and use information through the Site, and the choices you can make about the collection and use of your information.  This Policy also addresses information we collect from you when you schedule an appointment to be photographed, order photographs or other products from us, visit or are photographed at one of our studios or on-site photography locations, contact one of our customer service representatives, or respond to a survey or enter a contest or sweepstakes that we administer. 

**What information do you collect from and about me?**  
 _Information You Provide to Us_. We collect personal information (information that identifies you as an individual) and other information from you through your use of this Site, such as when you register for an account, schedule a photography appointment or place an order; when you visit or contact one of our studios, offices or customer service representatives; or when you respond to a survey or enter a contest or sweepstakes that we administer. This information may include some or all of the following:

  * your name
  * the names of and your relationship to family members or others Lifetouch is photographing as part of your photography session or whose photographs you wish to order
  * your physical address
  * your child’s birthdate
  * your email address
  * your telephone number(s)
  * credit card and other payment information
  * your photos and other content that you upload to the Lifetouch Site, if applicable (“ **Your Content** ”)

_Information You Provide About Others_. If you choose to share your photographs or other information with someone else through a Site feature, we will use the personal information you provide (for example the e-mail address of the recipient) to fulfill your request and for other purposes described in this Privacy Policy.   Please be aware that your name and/or email address could be provided to us by another user of the Site for the same purpose.

_Information from Other Sources_.  We may obtain personal information about you from other sources. For example, we may obtain data that is publicly available or from third party sources to improve the accuracy of and add to what we know about our customers,  in order to improve the relevance of the offers or product recommendations we provide you or enhance our ability to contact you, or for other purposes described in this policy. 

_Information from Social Networking and Third Party Services_.  A Site may allow you to interact with or through social networking services such as Facebook and Twitter ("Social Features"). Examples of Social Features include enabling you to "like" or "share" content or to log into a Site using your username and password for the third party social network. If you choose to connect your Lifetouch account with a third party social network, the social network may share information about you with us such as your public profile, e-mail address and friend list. If you choose to "like" or share content, information about you may be publicly displayed on the social network. You should review the privacy policy of that third party social network and check your privacy settings through that social network. If you post information on a social networking or other third party service that references Lifetouch or its products or services (e.g., via a Twitter hashtag), we may publish your post on a Site.

_Other information about you_. In addition to the personal information we collect as described above, the Site uses technology that collects certain non-personal technical information from your computer or mobile device over time and across different websites, such as what type of browser you are using, the website from which you enter the Site, and the pages you view as you tour our site. This technology, including cookies placed by third-party vendors, helps us compile statistics about our visitors and their use of our site. For example, we use Google Analytics cookies to understand high-level information about the age, gender, and interests of users of the Site. We use these statistics in connection with internal marketing programs and share them with third parties to improve our website design and content.  Our third party vendors may also use this information to provide you with Lifetouch advertisements on other websites and online services, and may combine this information with other information they gather about your visits to other websites and online services to show you advertisements that are more likely to be of interest to you (“Interest-Based Advertising”).    

_Cookies._  In addition to the personal information we collect as described above, the Lifetouch Site uses cookies and similar technologies that collect certain non-personal technical information from your computer or mobile device over time and across different websites, such as what type of browser you are using, the website from which you enter the Lifetouch Site, and the pages you view as you tour our site. This technology, including cookies placed by our third-party service providers, helps us customize your current and future visits to the site (for example, by storing the contents of your shopping cart until you are ready to check out), and it allows us to compile statistics about our visitors and their use of our site. We and our service providers use these statistics in connection with Lifetouch marketing programs and to improve our website design and content.  Our third party service providers may also use such technology to provide you with Lifetouch advertisements on other websites and online services, and may combine this technical information with other information they gather about your visits to other websites and online services to show you advertisements that are more likely to be of interest to you (“Interest-Based Advertising”).  

If you do not want the site to collect information through the use of cookies, you can set your web browser to reject cookies from the site or to alert you before a cookie is placed on your computer.  Each browser is different, so you should check your browser’s “Help” menu to learn how to change your cookie preferences.  Please note that cookie-based opt-outs only apply to the specific computer and browser on which the opt-out cookie is applied. If you accept a cookie, you can delete it at any time through your web browser.  However, if you choose not to accept cookies, you may not be able to take full advantage of some of this website’s features.  Also, the Network Advertising Initiative and the Digital Advertising Alliance offer opt-out tools to assist you in managing your choices for participating companies that use cookies for Interest-Based Advertising and cross-app advertising.  For more information about these tools please visit:[ NAI Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) (web browser only) and [DAA Opt-Out Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) (web browser only). You can also install Google Analytics' opt-out browser add-on by visiting <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**How does Lifetouch use the personal information it collects about me?**  
We responsibly limit the use and disclosure of your personal information. We may use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * to provide the products or services or benefits you request, or information about them,
  * to produce and deliver photographic products and services per our agreement with the organization you are affiliated with, as applicable,
  * to develop and improve our products and services,
  * to improve the content of our site and the services we provide, and their usefulness to you,
  * to deliver Lifetouch  marketing communications and promotional materials that may be of interest to you, and
  * to protect the security or integrity of our databases or website, to take precautions against liability, and to detect and remediate violations of our Terms & Condition or other misuse of the Site.

If you upload Your Content to a Site, it remains your property.  Lifetouch will only use Your Content to fulfill your orders and otherwise as directed by you.

Please be assured that Lifetouch does **not** use its customers’ photographs in marketing or advertising materials without first obtaining a release from the photo subject (or, in the case of a minor, the photo subject’s parent or legal representative). 

**Lifetouch does not sell, trade or share your personal information with unaffiliated third parties for their marketing purposes.   **  
We do share your personal information within Lifetouch and with J.C. Penney Company Inc.  for the purposes described in this Policy.  We may also share this information with third parties who provide support services to us such as helping us fulfill customer orders, process credit card orders and the like. If so, these parties are authorized to use the personal information solely in conjunction with the specific service they provide to or on behalf of Lifetouch.

We may also be required to share or transfer your personal information in other, limited circumstances, for example, to respond to judicial process, to comply with state, federal or local laws, to protect the security or integrity of our databases or website, to take precautions against liability, in the event of a corporate reorganization or, to the extent required by law, to provide information to law enforcement agencies.

**What choices do I have about your use of my personal information?**  
Our goal is to inform you about our products and services, including special promotions and coupons. However, if you are contacted and do not wish to receive further information, you may contact us at the phone number listed below, or for email: select _unsubscribe_ at the bottom of the email.

JCPenney Portraits  1-800-597-6453

We will act promptly to honor your request. Please allow 7-10 business days for your record to update in our system. However, even if we remove your information from use in our marketing programs, you may still receive offers and other promotional materials from Affiliated Companies, or from outside vendors or service providers who obtained your information before we received your request or from another source.

**How can I review and update the personal information you have about me?**  
If you would like to review, correct or delete your personal information, or if you are the parent or legal guardian of a minor and would like to review, correct or delete that minor's personal information, you may be able to do so by logging into your account with the Site.  If not, please contact us as noted below (see For further information).  There may be times when we are unable to fulfill your request - for example, if providing access to your personal information would reveal confidential commercial or proprietary information or personal information about someone else (and we cannot separate your data), if we are prohibited by law from disclosing the information or if we have a legal obligation to retain certain data. We may require additional personal information from you for the purposes of verifying your identity and rights. 

**How does Lifetouch safeguard personal information?**  
Lifetouch has implemented safeguards reasonably designed to protect against unauthorized access and disclosures of personal information under its control, including appropriate technical, physical and administrative safeguards and security measures. A comprehensive set of IT policies based on ISO 27001/2 governs information systems practices and procedures throughout the Lifetouch enterprise, and Lifetouch maintains third party certification of its compliance with the stringent Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard.  Please be advised, however, that despite these measures, no website, application, database or system is completely secure or “hacker proof”; accordingly, we cannot guarantee that our information security safeguards will never be compromised. 

**Other Information about this Policy**

**Your California Privacy Rights**  
Under California law, a California resident with whom a Lifetouch Company has an established relationship has the right to request certain information with respect to the types of personal information the company has shared with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, if any, and the identities of those third parties, within the immediately preceding calendar year, subject to certain exceptions. All requests for such information must be in sent by email to [ _privacyoffice@lifetouch.com_](mailto:privacyoffice@lifetouch.com).

Additionally, California residents under 18 who are registered users of a website can request removal of content or information posted by the user on this Site by emailing [ _privacyoffice@lifetouch.com_](mailto:privacyoffice@lifetouch.com) with “California Minor Content Removal Request” on the subject line and in the body of your message. Please specify in your request the URL of the website to which your request relates and the specific information or content you posted for which you are requesting removal.

**Children**  
The Site is intended for use by general audiences.  We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If a child has provided personal information through the Site, we ask that a parent or guardian contact the Site in writing at 11000 Viking Drive, Suite 400, Eden Prairie, MN 55344, Attention: Privacy Office or [_privacyoffice@lifetouch.com_](mailto:privacyoffice@lifetouch.com) and we will respond accordingly.

**No control of third party sites**  
Please be aware that websites that link to the Site, or which the Site links to, may collect personal information about you. You should consult the other sites’ privacy policies as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.

**Policy Updates**  
By using the Site, you consent to our use of your information as described in this Policy. As we implement new technology and introduce new services, or in response to changes in applicable laws or regulations, we will update the Policy, so we encourage you to review it often. We reserve the right to change our Online Privacy Policy at any time without advance notice. We will identify an updated version of this Policy with a revised effective date. Changes to our Policy will become effective when posted. If these changes materially affect how we use personal information collected from you prior to the date of the revised Policy, then we will obtain your consent to the revised Policy before applying it to that personal information.

**For further information**  
For further information regarding this website privacy statement or related Lifetouch policies and procedures, please contact: Privacy Office, Lifetouch Inc., 11000 Viking Drive, Eden Prairie, MN 55344; email:[ _privacyoffice@lifetouch.com_](mailto:privacyoffice@lifetouch.com) _._

Last Revised July 2016
